[Music]
in this video
i wish to share my own journey in
regards to
simple living everyone has a different
definition
on what this means and i think that's
perfectly fine
since everyone's life and choices are
unique
this is a little bit of my personal
[Music]
story
my lifestyle change was motivated by my
younger self
who was a far more anxious and fearful
person than i am now
i spent my teens and first years as an
adult saving money in any way i could
convinced it would somehow keep me safe
from the scary world
i lived as far below my means as
possible and save the rest
i worked long hours and had friends who
thought i was crazy for living the way i
did
in hindsight obsessively saving money
was a sign of a spiritual void
that i was trying to fill by attempting
to control what i could not
[Music]
as i matured i became more comfortable
spending money on things i needed
or that would add value to my life and
i've come a long way
since i now cherish investing in a cozy
and beautiful home
my hobbies and experiences
[Music]
so
do
however i have come to respect my
earlier choices as a teen
since it helped me achieve my dreams but
also made me realize that i needed to
grow
in wisdom and let go of my fear of
losing what i worked hard for
i now practice a far more moderate
version of that lifestyle
one that is motivated by seeking
internal fulfillment over being a
constant
consumer i now find deep enjoyment in
traveling and experiencing new things
while not relying on it to be happy
as a creative person i love decorating
my space and having access to all the
art supplies i need
i also like to house old books and
antiques
my own art and that of others in general
things of beauty
as well as purpose bring me joy so does
living in alignment with my beliefs
that we need to learn new habits of
consumption in order to build a brighter
tomorrow
and healthier earth
[Music]
while i am not emotionally reliant on
objects they
do add quality to my life especially my
books
and art of course having too much
creates clutter which is detrimental to
my peace of mind
i try to stop and consider each item
that i bring into my home
where it comes from what role it will
have i love to support small businesses
and second-hand shops
i'm far from perfect and i'm unable to
adhere to this philosophy
all the time but i try and that's all we
need to do
[Music]
i still live below my means and it keeps
my mind feeling peaceful while
motivating me to develop
my internal spirit i continue to save
and invest in my dreams
ensuring that my future will be that
much more stable because of it
i imagine owning my own home someday
being able to provide for my future
children
feeling free from the idea that i need
more and more and more to feel secure
instead this right now is enough
i believe in myself and my ability to
deal with situations as they come
i'm grateful for what i have and see it
is such a blessing to have my basic
needs
met
[Music]
i am enough as i am i cannot control the
future
i can make good choices but life is
unpredictable
and that's not a bad thing if i suddenly
lose everything i still have my soul
i'm doing just fine and so are you
i'm sending you my love and wish that
your year be abundant in every way that
your spirit needs
[Music]
do
you